Yu'er
钰儿
Come let the empress see you
过来让皇后看看你
How can this be?
这怎么能这样
Right
对呀
How can he not follow orders?
怎么能不听调令
Rashly attack
贸然进攻
But he did win the battle after all
可是仗人家毕竟是打赢了呀
Your Majesty arrives
陛下到
Pay respects to Your Majesty
拜见陛下
Let's all speak
都说说吧
What's the matter?
什么事啊
Your Majesty
陛下
I
臣
Wish to impeach Zhu Yuanzhi
要弹劾朱元之
Not long ago
前不久
Our Beishuo Army
我北朔军
Engaged in close combat with Wuzhao's Shixin division
与邬伖石信部短兵相接
The Ministry of War ordered General Zhu
兵部敕令朱将军
After repelling the enemy
击退敌人后
To withdraw and defend the base
退守驻地
But General Zhu did not follow orders
可朱将军不听调令
Privately advanced recklessly
私自冒进
Actually pursued deep into Wuzhao territory
竟然直追入邬伖腹地
Causing heavy losses to our troops
致使我军兵马损伤惨重
And disrupted Your Majesty's approved battle plan
还把陛下钦定的作战方针
Completely
全部都给打乱了
But no matter what
可不论怎么说
General Zhu achieved a great victory this time
朱将军这次取得大胜
The entire southern Pingzhou
整个平州南部
Was recovered by the Beishuo Army
都被北朔军收复
I think
臣觉得
Not only should he not be punished
不但不该罚
But should be heavily rewarded
还该重赏
To encourage the enterprising spirit of all
以鼓励天下人进取之心
I remember
我记得
The court only gave General Zhu
朝中只给了朱将军
Supplies to repel the enemy
退敌的粮饷
The money for his campaign
他打仗发兵的钱
Where did it come from?
是怎么来的
This Zhu Yuanzhi
这朱元之
Is almost declaring himself king
他就差割据称王了
He uses
他打着
Your Majesty's land reform as a banner
他打着陛下土地改革的旗号
In Qingzhou
在青州
Extensively seized land
大肆征收土地
Directly distributed to the army
直接分给军队
But General Zhu
可朱将军
Did successfully implement Your Majesty's new policies
也算成功推行了陛下的新政
This is a great merit
这是大功一件
Forcibly seized from great families
强抢大户豪绅
Privately divided court land
私分朝廷土地
This
他这
Is clearly
这分明就是
Bandit behavior
土匪行径
Alright, alright
好了好了
Stop arguing
别吵了
Let's put this matter aside for now
此事暂时压着吧
Discuss another day
改日再议
Court dismissed
散朝
This phoenix
这凤头
Has gotten fat recently
最近胖了
It seems
看来
Fan Zhong's meals are quite good
范忠这伙食弄得不错呀
Let's talk
说说吧
About General Zhu's matter
朱将军的事情
What do you think?
你们怎么看
Although General Zhu won a small victory
朱将军虽然赢得小胜
He so flagrantly ignored court orders
可他如此枉顾朝廷调令
If something major happens in the future
如若未来出了大事
And General Zhu still acts willfully
朱将军还是一意孤行
Cannot coordinate closely with the center
不能与中央紧密配合
This would be a catastrophic hole
这就是倾天的窟窿
Your son believes
儿臣以为
We cannot have wishful thinking
不能存有侥幸心理
Should be punished
该罚
A general in the field
将在外
May not always follow the ruler's orders
君命有所不受
The battlefield changes in an instant
战场上瞬息万变
If everything follows central orders
如果一切都听从中央调令
Then how do we seize opportunities?
那还抓什么战机
Since ancient times
自古以来
Victory and defeat are decided in an instant
胜负手都只在一瞬之间
Father
父皇
Your son believes
儿臣以为
General Zhu's intentions are correct
朱将军本心是正的
And he's brave and decisive
又骁勇果断
Should be rewarded
该赏
Xuan shall prosper
大宣当兴